Ernst Bacon Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1898-1990 (Box 1-27)
  - Great river - A symphony for narrator and orchestra, Holograph full score in ink; 104 p. (Box-folder 14b/1-2)
  - Ground hog, Holograph in ink for piano; 4 p. (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Ground hog, Holograph in ink for 2 violins and piano; 4 p. (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Habañera, Holograph in ink for piano; 2 p. (Box-folder 14b/3)
  - Hanon (Familiar sequence on the white keys), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/6)
  - The heart [S.l.]: Mercury Music Corporation, 1952., Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Heavy hangs the sky, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Heidi (11th chords in C), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Holy night, Holograph piano-vocal score with annotations; 1 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Hopscotch (slurs over the beat), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/11)
  - The humble birth, Photocopy of holograph chorus score; 3 p. (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Iceberg, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 5 p. each; 2 versions (Box-folder 3/13)
  - In that poor stable [S.l.]: Novello & Company Limited, 1973., Piano-vocal score; 6 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/14)
  - [Intrada], Holograph in ink for organ; 13 p. (Box-folder 3/15a)
  - [Intrada], Photocopy of holograph for organ [bound] 10 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/15b)
  - [Jehova and the ark], Holograph score for 2 pianos and annotations; 7 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 14b/4)
  - [Jehova and the ark], Photocopy of holograph for 2 pianos; [?] p.; incomplete (Box-folder 14b/5)
  - Jericho, Holograph score in ink for unspecified instruments; 2 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 14b/6)
  - Joshua Ebenezer Fry (a corn fantasy), Holograph for 2 pianos in ink; 3 p. (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Jota, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 2 p. (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Jota for guitar, Holograph in ink for piano; 10 p. (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Klamath River, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 4 p. (Box-folder 14b/7)
  - Koschatiana, Holograph for cello and piano in ink; 4 p. (Box-folder 3/19)
  - The last invocation: a requiem, Holograph full score; [62] p.; dedicated to the memory of Peggy Camp Bacon (1928-1966); Includes: 15/3 No.8 Song [Lingering last drops] Holograph score for unison chorus; [2] p. 15/4 The voice of the rain Holograph full score in ink; [22] p. (Box-folder 15/1)
  - The last invocation: a requiem, Holograph chorus score; [19] p.; incomplete (Box-folder 15/2)
  - The last invocation: a requiem, Holograph full score; [22] p.; unidentified pages (Box-folder 15/5)
  - The last invocation: a requiem, Holograph chorus score; [6] p.; unidentified pages (Box-folder 15/6)
  - The last invocation: a requiem, Holograph of choral parts and copyist manuscript of parts; [?] p.; incomplete (Box-folder 15/7)
  - The last invocation: a requiem, Photocopy of holograph full score, bound, with annotations; 87 p.; complete (Box-folder 15/8)
  - The last invocation: a requiem, Photocopy of holograph full score, unbound; 87 p.; complete (Box-folder 15/9)
  - The last invocation: a requiem, Photocopy of holograph full score;76 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 15/10)
  - [A life], Holograph score for cello and piano, earlier version 18 p. (Box-folder 16/1)
  - [A life], Photocopy of holograph score with markings; 27 p. (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Little girl walking to school (left hand syncopations), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Little jota, Holograph in ink for piano; 2 p. (Box-folder 3/21)
  - The long farewell [S.l.]: Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1951., Chorus score; 5 p.each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/22)
  - The lord star, Holograph full score in ink; 32 p. (Box-folder 16/2)
  - The lord star, Holograph chorus score in ink; 11 p.; Typewritten page of notes dated May 2 1988 (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Love somebody [S.l.]: Theodore Presser Company, 1957., Chorus score; 13 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/23)
  - Marinio, Holograph in ink for guitar with corrections and paste on; [2] p. (Box-folder 16/3)
  - Married and single life, Holograph for viola and piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/24)
  - Melody on a leaf, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 1 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/25)
  - 'Mid winter's snow [S.l.]: Lawson-Gould Music Publishers, Inc., 1976., Chorus score for two part treble chorus; 7 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/26)
  - The morning star, Holograph in ink for guitar; 5 p.; 2 versions (Box-folder 16/4)
  - Mother and child, Holograph score for cello and piano in ink; 2 p. (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Mother and child, Photocopy of holograph for keyboard; 2 p. (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Mt. Blanc, Holograph for piano with annotations; 2 p. (Box-folder 3/27)
  - The muffin man, Holograph full score in ink;16 p.; holograph parts with leaf in pencil; incomplete (Box-folder 16/6)
  - The muffin man, Photocopy of holograph bound full score; 28 p. (Box-folder 16/7)
  - The muffin man, Photocopy of holograph full score and parts;10 p.; early version (Box-folder 16/8)
  - [Music notebooks and unbound music notes], Holograph drafts and annotations (Box-folder 53b/1-2)
  - The Nantucket fling, Full score, holograph in ink; 34 p. (Box-folder 16/9)
  - The Nantucket fling, Photocopy of holograph full score bound and unbound; 34 p. each (Box-folder 16/9)
  - The Nantucket fling, Photocopy of printed parts (Box-folder 16/9)
  - Napoleon crossings the Alps, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 3/28)
  - Narcissus (where the left hand reflects the right in symmetric as well as pianistic inversion), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 3/29)
  - Necklace of cambiatas, holograph melodic lines; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/30)
  - Neusiedler See, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/31)
  - Night at the opera (Alberti bass), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/32)
  - Nixie's party/Nixie's barnyard see also: [White House blues] see also: [Watergate], Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 19 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 16/10)
  - The noble skewball, Holograph in ink for piano and unidentified instrument with annotations; 2 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 16/11)
  - [Octets for brass & percussion], Holograph scores in ink with annotations; 16 p. (Box-folder 16/12)
  - Ode to dusk, Holograph score in ink for piano and any instrument in range; 2 p.; slight water damage (Box-folder 16/13)
  - Okefenokee, Holograph score in ink for clarinet and piano; 4 p. (Box-folder 3/33)
  - The [old gray goose], Holographs for 2 pianos; 3 p.; 3 versions (Box-folder 16/14)
  - Omaha, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score, 3 p. (Box-folder 3/34)
  - [Organ tracings] see also: Spirits and places, Holograph scores in ink for organ;13 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 3/35)
  - Our refuge, Holograph chorus score in ink; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/36)
  - Papa and mama see: Copy cat
  - [Parliament of fowls], Holograph score in ink for piano; 41 p. (Box-folder 3/37)
  - Parotta (or Polinacha), Holograph in ink for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/38)
  - Parting for guitar, Holograph score; 4 p.; 2 versions (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Parting for guitar, Holograph draft; 1 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Pause for orchestra, Holograph full score in ink; 8 p. (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Peace, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score for low voice or unison chorus; 3 p. (Box-folder 3/39)
  - Pecos Bill (black against white), Holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Pecos Bill (black against white), Holograph draft for piano;1 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 17/3)
  - The Pequod-overture, Holograph full score;19 p.; unfinished (Box-folder 17/4)
  - "Peterborough, N.H.," suite for viola and piano, [in the memory of Mrs. Edward MacDowell, 1952], Holograph score with annotations and pasteovers, with holograph parts; 25 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 17/5)
  - "Peterborough, N.H.," suite for viola and piano, [in the memory of Mrs. Edward MacDowell, 1952], Photocopy and holograph score; 22 p. (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Petticoat slide (a lazy ländler), Holograph for flute, clarinet and bassoon in ink; 2 p. (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Petticoat slide (a lazy ländler), Photocopy of holograph for flute, clarinet and bassoon;1 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Pieces for band, Photocopy of holograph full score; 77 p. (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Pieces for band, Copyist's manuscript of parts (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Pilgrim hymn, Photocopy of score for unison chorus and organ/piano accompaniment; 2 p. (Box-folder 23/40)
  - The politician, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 2 p. (Box-folder 3/41)
  - Prelude (alternative orchestration for prelude), Holograph full score in ink; 4 p. (Box-folder 3/42)
  - Prelude and fugue for large orchestra, Holograph in ink bound full score; 52 p.; Includes: Two songs for bass (Box-folder 17/12)
  - Prologue to "Everyman", Holograph score for cello, organ, and/or piano; 8 p. (Box-folder 17/13)
  - The purple taffic, Holograph full score in ink; 4 p. (Box-folder 3/43)
  - The Pusta (a Transylvania fantasy for violin and piano), Holograph score in ink for violin and piano; 19 p. (Box-folder 17/14)
  - Pusta (the vibrato intense), Holograph score in ink for cello and piano; 14 p. (Box-folder 17/14)
  - Quiet halleluia for solo guitar, Holograph in ink for guitars; 2 p. (Box-folder 3/44)
  - Quiet halleluyah for guitar, Holograph in ink; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/45)
  - Quintet see: Tempest
  - The rain forest, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/46)
  - Ratattoo, Holograph in ink for piano; 2 p. (Box-folder 3/47)
  - Ratattoo, Holograph in ink for piano; 1 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 3/47)
  - Red Cross hymn, Photocopy of copyist's holograph of close score; 4 p. (Box-folder 3/48)
  - Remembering Ansel Adams/In memory, Holograph in ink full score with drafts and rejected draft; 89 p.; 2 versions (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Return of spring [S.l.]: Lawson-Gould Music Publishers, Inc., 1958., Chorus score; 1 leaf each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/49)
  - Riolama (ostinato of 4 chords), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/50)
  - Riolama (ten places for piano and orchestra) with supplement [Concerto for piano no.1], Holograph full score in ink; 152 p. (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Riolama (ten places for piano and orchestra) with supplement [Concerto for piano no.1], Photocopy of holograph full score with paste over and annotations; [bound] 146 p. (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Riolama (ten places for piano and orchestra) with supplement [Concerto for piano no.1], Holograph in ink for 2 pianos; 78 p. (Box-folder 19/4)
  - The river queen [S.l.]: American music edition, 1962., Two piano score; 12 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/51)
  - [Rounds and canons 2, 3, & 4 voices], Holographs in ink for vocal with little or optional accompaniment; 31 p. (Box-folder 19/5)
  - [Rounds and canons 2, 3, & 4 voices], Photocopy of holograph for 3 voices and piano or organ; 1 p. (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Saluda, N.C., Photocopy of holograph score for unspecified instruments; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/52)
  - Salute to Casey Jones for 4 or more cellos, Holograph score in ink with corrections; 7 p. (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Salisbury cycle for English bells, Holograph score in ink for English bells; 19 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 4/1)
  - The schoolboy [S.l.]: Lawson-Gould Music Publishers, Inc., 1958., Chorus score for two part chorus; 6 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Second time skating (shifting seconds) see: First time skating
  - Seldom seen hollow (melody in the left and right hands) [S.l.]: Theodore Presser Company, 1963., Piano; 1 leaf each; 2 copies (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Sleep song [S.l.]: Rongwen Music, Inc., 1955., Chorus Score; 5 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 4/4)
  - So set its sun in thee, Photocopy of printed music; 4 p. (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Soft air, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Sonata for cello and piano, Holograph score in ink; 36 p. (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Sonata for viola and piano, Holograph full score; 67 p.; incomplete early edition with some water damage (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Sonata for viola and piano, Holograph full score, 1987;46 p.; incomplete early edition (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Sonata for viola and piano, Printed and bound viola part and photocopied parts with printed paste over parts three movements (Box-folder 14b/8-11)
  - Sonata for viola and piano, Photocopy of holograph full score [bound] and photocopies of printed full scores; [bound and unbound] 57 p. each (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Sonata for violin and piano, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score; [bound] 30 p. with photocopy of copyist parts (Box-folder 14b/12)
  - Song after the rain [S.l.]: Rongwen Music, Inc., 1959., Score for horn and piano;3 p. and 1 part each; 2 copies (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Song of snow-white heads [S.l.]: Mercury Music Corporation, 1952., Photocopy of a piano-vocal score; 4 p. (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Songs from Emily Dickinson, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score; 36 p. each; Published by Ernst Bacon, n.d.; 2 copies (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Songs of the people, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 32 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 4/10)
  - [Songs of A. E. Housman] [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; 30 p. (Box-folder 4/11)
  - [Songs with lyrics by C. Lengyal], Holograph piano-vocal scores in ink; 12 p. (Box-folder 4/12)
  - The sophomore little hymnal, Photocopy of student's holographs; 9 p.; a collaboration of E. Bacon and students of Converse College (Box-folder 4/13)
  - [Spirits and places] see also: [Organ tracings], Holograph in ink for organ; 50 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Stars, Holograph piano-vocal score; 2 p. (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Stars, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 2 p. (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Stony-lonesome, Holograph score in ink for oboe and piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Stony-lonesome, Holograph sketch in ink for oboe, piano, violin, viola, cello, and bass; 1 p. (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Stony-lonesome, Photocopy of holograph score for oboe and piano; 3 p. each; 2 copies, second is longer version than previous holograph (Box-folder 4/16)
  - String quartet, Holograph score in ink, with annotations; 65 p.; unfinished with drafts (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Sugarlump, Holograph for unspecified instruments with annotations; 2 p. (Box-folder 14b/13)
  - Sunday (pedal) see: Hopscotch (slur over the beat)
  - A stroll, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 2 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Swamp and meadow, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Holograph full score movement 1 with annotations; [bound] 48 p. (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Holograph full score movement 2 with annotations; [bound] 59 p. (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Holograph full score movement 3 with annotations; [bound] 48 p. (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Holograph full score movement 4 with annotations; [bound] 53 p. (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Photocopy of holograph full score, movement 1; [2 copies, bound] 48 p. each (Box-folder 21/1)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Photocopy of holograph full score, movement 2; [2 copies, bound] 58 p. each (Box-folder 21/2)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Photocopy of holograph full score, movement 3; [2 copies, bound] 45 p. each (Box-folder 21/3)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Photocopy of holograph full score, movement 4; [2 copies, bound] 53 p. each (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Holograph of full score movement 3 with annotations; [bound] [?] p. (Box-folder 22a/1)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Holograph of full score 4 movements; 197 p. (Box-folder 22a/2-4)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Holograph parts; [?] p.; Parts for flute 1 and 2, oboe 1 and 2, bassoon and contra bassoon, horn 1-4, trumpet in C 1-3, and trombone 1-3 and photocopies of holographs for all string parts (Box-folder 22a/5-7)
  - Symphony [No.1] in 4 movements, Negative of holograph full score 4 movements (Box-folder 22a/8-9, Box-folder 22b/1-2)
  - Take your choice, Holograph of four songs 3 piano-vocal, 1 full score; 10 p. (Box-folder 23/1)
  - Take your choice, Copyist's manuscript parts in ink; [?] p. (Box-folder 22b/3-8)
  - Take your choice, Copyist's manuscript parts in ink; [?] p.; 1st version (B) (Box-folder 23/2)
  - Take your choice, Copyist's manuscript miscellaneous parts in ink; [?] p.; Med. -War (Box-folder 23/3-4)
  - Take your choice, Photocopy of holographs and copyist's manuscript for piano-vocal score; 48 p.; spiral bound (Box-folder 23/5-6)
  - Take your choice, Photocopy of holograph and copyist's manuscript for piano-vocal miscellaneous songs some with annotation; 19 p. (Box-folder 23/7)
  - [Tempest], Holograph Score with parts in ink; 45 p. (Box-folder 24a/1)
  - [Tempest], Holograph score in ink; 39 p.; Syracuse version (Box-folder 24a/2)
  - [Tempest], Holograph piano-vocal score in ink; 36 p.; Stratford version (Box-folder 24a/3)
  - [Tempest], Holographs score in ink, movements 1,2 and 5; 47 p. (Box-folder 24a/4)
  - [Tempest], Holograph string parts and narration parts (Box-folder 24b/1)
  - [Tempest], Photocopy of holograph score spiral bound;49 p.; Converse College version (Box-folder 24b/2)
  - [Tempest], Photocopy of holograph full score; 47 p. (Box-folder 24b/3)
  - [Tempest], Photocopy of holograph and copyist's manuscript parts (Box-folder 24b/4)
  - Ten songs, Piano-vocal score; 35 p. each; Published by Ernst Bacon, 1928; 2 copies (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Three fables (narrative rubato style), Photocopy of holograph for piano and narrator; 1 p. (Box-folder 4/20)
  - Three little babes, Holograph for two violins (and a 3rd), or two clarinets (and a 3rd), or oboe or flute and bassoon; 1 p. (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Three little babes, Holograph for 2 violins, or 2 violas, or 2 oboes, or 1 flute and 1 oboe, or 2 clarinets (transposing); 3 p. (Box-folder 4/21)
  - The Tin Lizzie, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 4/5)
  - To a loving husband: a songlet for soprano and alto, Photocopy of holograph for piano-vocal score; [1 p.]; 2copies (Box-folder 4/23)
  - [To the United Nations] see also: Destiny of the flag, Holograph drafts of full score and parts (Box-folder 24b/5)
  - [To the United Nations], Copyist’s holograph for 2 violins, viola, cello and bass with oboe parts; Concord ode (Box-folder 24b/6)
  - Toucanacha, Holograph for piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Two songs for bass see: Prelude and fugue for large orchestra
  - Transylvania/Homage to Lizst, Holograph score in ink for cello and piano; 14 p. (Box-folder 24a/5)
  - A tree on the plains, Holograph full score in ink; 251 p. (Box-folder 24a/6-8)
  - A tree on the plains, Holograph piano score 2 hands or 4 hands in ink; 158 p. (Box-folder 25/1-3)
  - A tree on the plains. Buddy's nocturne, Holograph part for clarinet; 1 p.; discarded part (Box-folder 25/4)
  - A tree on the plains. Shirley's tap dance, Photocopy of holograph for 2 pianos; 3 p.; copied backwards (Box-folder 25/4)
  - Tributaries songs, Holograph piano-vocal in ink with annotations; 97 p. (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Tributaries songs [S.l.]: The Musical Offering, 1978., Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 108 p. each; published [limited edition] by The Musical Offering, 1978; 2 copies (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Trio No.1 for violin, cello, and piano (revised version), Holograph score with annotations for violin, cello, and piano; 50 p. (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Trio No.1 for violin, cello, and piano (revised version), Photocopy of holograph score for violin, cello and piano (first version); [bound]; movement 1, revised 1980 with corrections in red (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Trio No.1 for violin, cello, and piano (revised version), Copyist's manuscript parts in pencil (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Trio No.2, Holograph score for violin, cello, and piano with holograph annotations; [?] p. (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Trio No.2, Photocopy of holograph for violin, cello and piano with printed parts; [?] p. (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Trio [No.3?], Holograph piano part only; [?] p.; incomplete (Box-folder 26/6)
  - [Trio], Holographs in ink with annotations; 26 p. (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Trio, Holographs with annotations; [?] p.; some photocopies of holographs; drafts, sketches, and discards (Box-folder 26/8)
  - Trumpet tune see: [Intrada]
  - [Tumbleweeds suite], Holograph score for violin and piano with annotations, pasteovers, and draft; 41 p. (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Two poems for narrator and instrumental trio see also: Aliens, Photocopy of holograph score for narrator, oboe, horn, and piano;19 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 26/9)
  - Two hymns for the bicentennial [S.l.]: World Library Publications Inc., 1975., Close score; 4 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 6/3)
  - [Undeveloped titled sketches], Holographs of various mediums some with holograph annotations and pastovers; 30 p. (Box-folder 54/2)
  - [Unidentified ensemble and orchestra pages], Holograph pages in ink with annotations; 57 p. (Box-folder 54/3)
  - [Unidentified keyboard drafts], Holographs in ink some with annotations and pasteovers; 155 p. (Box-folder 54/4)
  - [Unidentified string ensemble pages], Holographs pages in ink with annotations; 18 p. (Box-folder 54/5)
  - [Unidentified parts], Holographs, negatives and photocopies of various parts; 30 p. (Box-folder 54/6)
  - [Unidentified drafts], Holographs in ink with annotations; 86 p. (Box-folder 54/7)
  - [Unfinished Symphonic Movement], Holograph full score in ink with annotations; 22 p. (Box-folder 54/8)
  - Usania, Holograph chorus score with annotations and script; 42 p. (Box-folder 26/10)
  - Usania, Photocopy of holograph full score; 64 p. (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Usania, Photocopy of copyist's chorus score with photocopy of holograph finale; 42 p. (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Valley of Judea [S.l.]: Lawson-Gould Publishers, Inc., 1977., Score for two part treble chorus with piano or organ and recorder; 10 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 6/4)
  - [Violin and piano pieces], Holograph scores in ink; 19 p. (Box-folder 27/3)
  - [Violin and piano pieces], Photocopy of holograph full score; 39 p. (Box-folder 27/4)
  - The violin see: Conversation
  - Voyage to Ararat, Holograph 2 piano score; 41 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Voyage to Ararat, Photocopy of holograph 2 piano score; 45 p.; complete (Box-folder 27/6)
  - Voyage to Ararat, Copyist's manuscript 2 piano score; 7 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Waiting [S.l.]: Peer International Corporation, 1956., Chorus score; 5 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Water [S.l.]: Galaxy Music Corporation, 1959., Two part treble chorus with piano or organ accompaniment; 4 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 6/6)
  - [Watergate] see also: Nixie's party, Holograph piano-vocal score; 24 p. (Box-folder 6/7)
  - [Watergate] see also: Nixie's party, Holograph piano-vocal score;24 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 6/8)
  - [Watergate] see also: Nixie's party, Photocopies of holographs with lyric sheets; [bound] 32 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 6/9)
  - [White House blues] see also: [Watergate] see also: Nixie's party, Holograph piano-vocal score with annotations; 62 p.; Includes: 53b/7-9 Scripts, notes and drafts, some autographs, typewritten, and photocopy 53b/7-9 Holograph corrections on drafts and script (Box-folder 27/8)
  - [White House blues], Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score, some with holograph annotations; 72 p. (Box-folder 27/9)
  - [White House blues], Drafts and discards, some holographs (Box-folder 27/10)
  - White marsh, Holograph full score, with annotations; 8 p. (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Wild mustangs/Texas/Lobo girl of Devil River see also: Riolama [Concerto for piano no. 1] 4th movement, Holograph in ink for piano; 13 p. (Box-folder 6/11)